Kelvin Kamara, Manchester

All enquiries should be directed to kelvinkamara@protonmail.com

Interview Availability

ASAP

Personal Profile

Born & raised in South East London, I have excellent IT skills. I am an extremely good time keeper with outstanding organisational skills and I am always willing to learn new skills. I am friendly, helpful and polite, with a good sense of humour. I am able to work both independently and in a team setting in busy environments. I am outgoing, tactful and capable of listening effectively when solving problems. Most importantly: I am dedicated and committed to performing to the best of my ability, and I am a person who strives to complete personal targets and milestones.

I have 8 years programming experience dabbling in all kinds of technologies and over 3 years commercial development experience directing my focus on monolithic web applications.

Location

I currently reside in Manchester. For roles based outside of this area I am willing to commute or work remotely until I can secure housing near the desired location.

Key Skills

- Portfolio: https://github.com/kkamara
- Languages: PHP, Python, NodeJS, Golang, SQL, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Bash, Ruby
- Frameworks/Libs: Laravel, React, Codeigniter, JQuery, Django, Bootstrap, Less, Symfony
- Popular APIs: Amazon Web Services Lambda, oauth2, Google Analytics, Google Gmail
- Fast & Proficient IT: 84 wpm typing speed
- Operating Systems: GNU+Linux (Debian), Windows XP/Vista/7/8.1/10
- Tools: Shell, Git, SVN, MySQL Workbench, PhpMyAdmin, VScode, Vim, Composer, NPM

Education

- Level 3 Information Technology Diploma: Double Grade Merit Merit
- CCNA Networking for Home and Small Businesses: Achieved
- GCSE Media Studies: Grade B
- GCSE English Literature: Grade B
- GCSE Information Technology: Grade C
- GCSE Mathematics: Grade C
- GCSE English Language: Grade C

Awards

UK GOVERNMENT CABINET OFFICE RECOGNITION AWARD (2019)



This award is in recognition of the valuable contribution you have made in delivering a critical

part of the Cabinet Office's Brexit preparation work, the Find a Tender service. During this period, you have gone above and beyond, demonstrating delivery against the Cabinet Office's purpose at the centre of government in:

- supporting the design and implementation of HM Government's policies and the Prime Minister's priorities.
- ensuring the delivery of the finest public services by improving the efficiency of



government.

Career History

NQC Ltd. (January 2019 - Present)

Software Developer

Working on systems that support some of the world's biggest public and private sector organisations, I am a developer in the team dedicated to our UK GOV client. My work for NQC and UK Gov has included building and extending features for large and complex software solutions. This is a position that involves working with PHP, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Java, Bash, Selenium Server.

PARK SMART SOLUTIONS (June 2017 - July 2018)

Web Developer

Working extensively with Codeigniter and AngularJS 1.x on multiple, linking software packages within a small team to meet deadlines. I created a portal appeal system that liaises between multiple software packages. I created a mobile anpr system. I created a static anpr system (my most complex project to work on to date) which includes working with AWS Lambda and Cloudwatch services. I also built a pcn payment solution for which I was compensated to do in my spare time.

OPTIMIA (March 2017 - June 2017)

Web Developer

Building modern websites using Wordpress.

Hobbies & Interests

You can usually find me coding away towards projects at github.com or a freelance project, catching up with friends or doing some form of enjoyable exercise such as bike riding and jogging.

References available on request.